Finding Aid for the Horace Marden Albright Papers LSC.2056
UCLA Library Special Collections
Horace Marden Albright papers
1918-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
Albright, Horace M. (Horace Marden), 1890-1987
LSC.2056
6 oversize_boxes
Horace Marden Albright (1890-1987) worked for the Federal government in the U.S. Department of the Interior (1915-17)and co-founded the U.S. National Park Service serving as assistant director (1917-19) and director (1929-33). She was also the first superintendent of Yellowstone National Park (1919-29). The collection consists of correspondence, printed materials, and photographs related to Albright's career as a conservationist and as director of the U.S. National Park Service.
378 boxes (189 linear ft.)
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Horace M. Albright, 1973.
Biography
Albright was born in Bishop, California, on January 6, 1890; graduated, University of California at Berkeley (1912) and Georgetown University Law School (1914); assistant to Secretary of the Interior, 1913-15; assistant attorney, U.S. Department of the Interior, 1915-17; co-founded U.S. National Park Service with Steven Mather, 1916; assistant director, U.S. National Park Service, 1917-19; first superintendent of Yellowstone National Park, 1919-29; second director, U.S. National Park Service, 1929-33; vice-president and general manager, U.S. Potash Company, 1933-46; awards received include University of California Alumnus of the Year (1952), American Forestry Association Distinguished Service Award (1968), Audubon Medal (1969), Medal of Freedom (1980); died in 1987.
Chronology
Missing Title
January 6, 1890: Born in Bishop, California.
1912: Graduated: University of California, Berkeley.
1914: Georgetown University Law School.
1913-1915: Served as assistant to Secretary of Interior Franklin K. Lane.
1915-1917: Assistant Attorney, Department of Interior, assigned to national park affairs.
1916: Co-founded National Park Service with Steven Mather.
1917-1919: Assistant Director, National Park Service.
1919-1929: First Superintendent of Yellowstone National Park.
1929-1933: Second Director of National Park Service. After leaving it in 1933, Horace M. Albright maintained a close personal interest in the affairs of the NPS until the early 1970s. For 6 years he served as a member of the National Park Service Advisory Board, and later he joined the council of that board. He also remained in close contact with succeeding directors of the National Park Service, as can be seen in his correspondence.
1933-1946: Vice-President and General Manager, U.S. Potash Company. Throughout his time with U.S. Potash Company, Horace M. Albright continued to be extremely active in a very wide range of conservation causes.
Awards for Conservation Work and other Honors
1926: The Order of the Northern Star (Sweden).
1933: Pugsley Gold Medal of the American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society.
1952: Alumnus of the Year at the University of California.
1956: Honorary degree - University of Montana.
1959: Theodore Roosevelt Association Distinguished Service Medal.
1961: Honorary Degree - University of California.
1962: Gold Medal of the Camp Fire Club of America.
1962: Honorary Degree - University of New Mexico.
1968: American Forestry Association Distinguished Service Award.
1968: Berkeley Fellow.
1969: Audubon Medal.
1980: Medal of Freedom - the nation's highest civilian award.
Conservation Groups Active In
American Forestry Association - Honorary Vice-President.
American Planning and Civic Association - Chairman of the Board.
American Pioneer Trails Association - Vice-President.
American Scenic and HIstoric Preservation Society - Trustee and Vice President.
American Society of Landscape Architects - Corresponding member.
Campfire Club Conservation Committee - Consultant.
Colonial Williamsburg - member, Board of Trustees
Death Valley 49ers - Honorary Vice-President.
Desert Protective Council - Director.
Hudson River Conservation Society - Second Vice-President.
Jackson Hole Preserve - Trustee.
National Conference on State Parks - member and co-founder in 1921.
National Parks Association - Board of Trustees.
National Park Service Advisory Board.
National Trust for HIstoric Preservation.
Pacific Tropical Botanical Garden in Hawaii - Trustee and President.
Palisades Interstate Park Commission.
Resources for the Future - Chairman of the Board and co-founder.
Save the Redwoods League - Member of Council.
Sierra Club - Honorary Vice-President.
Other Interests
National Outdoors Resources Review Commission - on advisory board.
Member of Hoover Commission to reorganize executive branch of federal government.
National Minerals Advisory Council.
American Institute Mining and Metallurgical Engineers.
American Potash Institute.
Potash Export Institute.
Clubs: Cosmos, Boone and Crockett, Explorer's Century.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, printed materials, and photographs related to Albright's career as a conservationist and as director of the U.S. National Park Service from 1929-33.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence (Boxes 1-52).
Printed material (Boxes 53-218).
Items collected during travels (Boxes 219-230).
Magazines, bulletins, printed materials (Boxes 245-378).
Horace M. Albright lectures (Box 244).
Miscellaneous subjects (Boxes 245-378).
Oversize material (Boxes 379-385).
Related Material
Horace Marden Albright collection of printed material regarding national parks (Collection 1444). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA. Unpublished inventory of Collection 1444 is available upon request.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 462164
Photographs.; Parks -- Government policy.; Conservation of natural resources.; Albright, Horace M. (Horace Marden),1890-1987--Archives; United States--National Park Service--Archival resources.; United States--National Park Service--History.
- Correspondence: Personal and General
  - A - F. (Box 1)
  - F - K. (Box 2)
  - K - M. (Box 3)
  - M - R. (Box 4)
  - R - S. (Box 5)
  - T - Z. (Box 6)
  - American Heritage. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Harvey. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Bartlett, Dr. Richard A. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Crampton, Louis C. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Goodwin, T.R. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Gugler, Eric., 1960-1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Gugler, Eric., 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Haynes, Isabel and Jack. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - O'Brien, Robert. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Povah, Trevor. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Reader's Digest. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller, Laurence. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Taylor, Frank J. and Katherine Ames. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Twitchell, Colonel Heath. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fortune Magazine Tribute to HMA., 1963 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous cards and postcards. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous cards and postcards. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - 1914-1916. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1920-1922. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1923-1925. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1926. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1927. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1933, 1934 and 1939. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1940-1949. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - 1950-1956. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - 1957-1958. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1959. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - 1960. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - January-July 1961. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - August-October 1961. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - November-December 1961. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - January-April 1962. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - May-July 1962. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - August-December 1962. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - January-April 1963. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - January-May 1963. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - July-August 1963. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - September 1963. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - October 1963. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - November-December 1963. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - January-February 1964. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - March-May 1964. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - June-September 1964. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - October-December 1964. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - January 1965. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - February-April 1965. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - May-June 1965. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - July-August 1965. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - September-December 1965. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - January-March 1966. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - April-June 1966. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - July-September 1966. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - October-December 1966. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - January 1967. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - February 1967. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - March-April 1967. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - May-July 1967. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - August-September 1967. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - October 1967. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - November-December 1967. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - January-February 1968. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - March-May 1968. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - June 1968. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - July 1968. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - August-September 1968. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - October-November 1968. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - December 1968. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - January 1969. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - February 1969. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - March-April 1969. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - May-June 1969. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - July-August 1969. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - September-October 1969. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - November-December 1969. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - January-February 1970. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - March-May 1970. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - June-July 1970. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - August 1970. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - September-December 1970. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1971. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1972. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - January-February 1973. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - March-May 1973. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - June-July 1973. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - August 1973. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - September-December 1973. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Foreign friends., 1938, 1956-1970 (Box 15, Folder 7-11)
    - 1938, 1956-1958. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - 1959. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1960. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - 1961. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - 1962-1970. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Foreign friends, miscellaneous. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Summer trip., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents note
    Correspondence and news clippings.
  - Correspondence concerning Solinsky Affair., 1934 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lists of HMA's personal connections. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - [illegible] Miller -- scripts and articles. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Newport, Rhode Island: memorabilia., 1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Magazine articles and clippings. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous printed papers. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous printed papers, news clippings. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 17, Folder 1-3)
  - Miscellaneous invitations and programs. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous invitations. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - News clippings. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - News clippings., (14 folders) (Box 18-20)
- Correspondence: About National Parks
  General note
  [Arranged by park; also contains clippings, ephemera, photos, etc.]
  - A - E. (Box 21)
  - F - Grand Teton. (Box 22)
  - Great Smokies - H. (Box 23)
  - I - N. (Box 24)
  - N - P. (Box 25)
  - R - W. (Box 26)
  - Yellowstone. (Box 27)
  - Yosemite - Z. (Box 28)
- Correspondence: Arranged by Agency
  [Also some business papers and printed material]
  - American Conservation Association, Incorporated. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - American Forestry Association. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - American History Club. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - American Mining Congress. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - American Native Study Society. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - American Pioneer Trails Association. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - American Planning and Civic Association, miscellaneous. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - American Planning and Civic Association, plus correspondence., 1939-1941 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - American Planning and Civic Association National Conference on State Parks., 1938 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - American Society of Landscape Architects. (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Bishop Museum and Historical Society. (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Boone and Crockett Club (Box 30-31)
    - Business papers. (Box 30, Folder 3-6)
    - Handbooks., 1965 and 1967 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Publications and handbooks., 1961, 1963, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo Bill Memorial Association. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Bureau of Land Management, Department of the Interior. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Bureau of Outdoor Recreation, Department of the Interior. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Department of Reclamation. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - California Conservation Council. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - California Tomorrow. (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Camp Fire Club of America. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    Correspondence.
  - Camp Fire Club of America. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Printed papers.
  - Charles Darwin Foundation for the Galapagos Islands. (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - A Christian Ministry in the National Parks (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Business papers. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Citizen's Committee on Natural Resources. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Clampus Vitus. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Colonial Williamsburg. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Committee for the Preservation of the Tule Elk. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Conservation Associates. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - The Conservation Foundation. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Conservation Law Society of America. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Death Valley 49ers. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Defenders of San Gorgonio Wilderness. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Defense Orientation Conference Association. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Denver Public Library; conservation library center. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Desert Protective Council (Box 33, Folder 6-9)
    - Business papers. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Newsletter, El Paisano. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - J.N. "Ding" Darling Foundation (Box 33, Folder 10-11)
    - Business papers and correspondence. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Publications. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Downtown Lowes Manhattan Association. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Eastern California Museum, Independence, California. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Eastern National Park and Monument Association. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Explorer's Club. (Box 33, Folder 15)
    Business papers.
  - Explorer's Club. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Forest History Society (Box 34, Folder 3-5)
    - Business papers. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Annual meeting., 1971 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Fort Massac, Illinois. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Foundation of America. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Friends of the Earth. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Friends of the National Zoo. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Friends of the Santa Monica Mountains, parks and sea shore. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Grand Teton Lodge Company. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Greater Los Angeles Zoo Association. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Hudson River Conservation Society. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - The Institute of Early American History and Culture. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Includes International Commission on National Parks.
  - Izaak Walton League. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Jackson Hole Preserve, Incorporated. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Keep America Beautiful. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Keep Tahoe Blue. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Lewis and Clark Trail Commission. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Mettlers Wood Campaign. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Montana Historical Society. (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - The Mountaineers. (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Museum of Navajo Ceremonial Art. (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Museum of New Mexico, Santa Fe, New Mexico. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - National Audubon Society -- Corkscrew Cypress Swamp, Coral Gables, Florida. (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - National Audubon Society and others. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - National Committee for the Wildflowers of the United States. (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - National Conference on State Parks. (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - National Conference on State Parks. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Business papers and correspondence.
  - National Foundation for Economic Stability. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - National Foundation for Junior Museums. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - National Park Foundation. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - National Park Service, 1917-1973 (Box 36-39)
    - National Park Service correspondence, 1917-1958 (Box 36, Folder 5-10)
      - 1917-1919. (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - 1922-1929. (Box 36, Folder 6)
      - 1933-1936. (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - 1940-1948. (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - 1953-1957. (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - January-June 1958. (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - National Park Service correspondence, 1958-1970 (Box 37, Folder 1-12)
      - July-August 1958. (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - 1959-1960. (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - 1961. (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - 1962. (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - 1963. (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - 1964. (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - 1965. (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - 1966. (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - 1967. (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - 1968. (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - 1969. (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - 1970. (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - National Park Service correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
      - 1971. (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - 1972-1973. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Park Development Conference., 1957 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases, 1954-1973 (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
      - 1954-1962. (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - 1965-1973. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - History of Science. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Mission 66. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Memoranda. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Centenary. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - The Madison Campfire., September 19, 1870 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Printed papers. (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Northeast Region Annual Report. (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - National Parks Association, 1952-1967 (Box 39, Folder 2-10)
    - National Parks Association correspondence, 1952-1967 (Box 39, Folder 2-3)
      - 1952-59. (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - 1960-67. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Evidence on National Parks given at Congressional Hearing., 1962 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous association papers. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Printed papers and news clippings. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Plant Food Institute. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Recreation and Park Association. (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Trust for Historic Preservation. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Wildlife Federation. (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - National Area Council. (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Native Centers for Young America. (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - The Native Conservancy (Box 40, Folder 1-3)
    - Printed papers. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Business papers. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence. (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Nevada State Parks System. (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - New York State Historical Association. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - New York Zoological Society. (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission, 1961 and n.d. (Box 40-41)
    - Report by National Planning Association, Parts 1-2., 1961 (Box 40, Folder 7-8)
    - Reports. (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
  - Overseas National Parks. (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Pacific Coast Borax Company. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Pacific Science Board. (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Tropical Botanical Garden (Box 41-42)
    - Business papers. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1964-1973 (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - 1964-1969. (Box 42, Folder 1)
      - 1970, 1972, 1973. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Legal statement, news clippings. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Palisades Interstate Park Commission (Box 42, Folder 4-8)
    - Long Island. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Palisades Parkway. (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - New York State Thruway. (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Trap Rock. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Palisades Native Association. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Park Association of New York City. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Peabody Museum, Harvard Museum. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Philips Laboratories. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Powdermill Native Reserve. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Ranier National Park Company. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Rancho Santa Fe. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Resources for the Future (Box 43-44)
    - Business papers. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - News clippings/business papers. (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Printed papers, annual report., 1967 (Box 43, Folder 8-10)
    - Annual reports., 1965-1966 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1972 (Box 44, Folder 2-4)
      - 1952-1953. (Box 44, Folder 2)
      - 1954-1965. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - 1966-1972. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Resources in the U.S. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Santa Barbara Botanical Garden. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Save San Francisco Bay Association. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - School of American Research, Santa Fe, New Mexico. (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Sequoia and Kings Canyon National Parks Company. (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Sierra Club (Box 45-47)
    - Annual Reports of Committees. (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports of Local Chapters. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Council Meetings. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1971 (Box 45, Folder 4-7)
      - 1947-1957. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - 1959-1960. (Box 45, Folder 5)
      - 1961-1965. (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - 1967-1971. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Organizational meetings of Board of Directors. (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Board of directors, minutes of regular meetings., end 1964 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Board of Directors, minutes of regular meetings., 1965-1972 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Minutes of special meetings. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Executive Committee - minutes of meetings, 1966-1972 (Box 46, Folder 2-3)
      - 1966. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - 1967-1972. (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Conservation Committee minutes., 1949-1972 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - David Brower affair. (Box 46, Folder 5-7)
    - Memoranda., 1963-1968 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Press releases., 1963-1968 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Mailings to members., 1965-1970 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous newsletters. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Business papers and news clippings. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Papers., 1949-1969 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Publications. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Sinclair Oil Company, National Parks Campaign., 1956 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Society for the Preservation of the Crow. (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Student Conservation Association (Box 47-48)
    - Business papers. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Papers., 1973 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Association (Box 48, Folder 2-3)
    - Correspondence. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Papers. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Trustees for Conservation. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Department of the Interior. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Geological Survey, Department of the Interior (Box 48, Folder 6-7)
    - Background information. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Wilderness Society. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - World Wildlife Fund. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous conservation groups (Box 49, Folder 3-4)
    - A - G. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - H - Z. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous papers. (Box 49, Folder 5-7)
  - Miscellaneous printed papers. (Box 49, Folder 8-9)
  - Miscellaneous printed papers. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous speeches and articles. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous magazine articles. (Box 50, Folder 3-5)